Lowe, Adolf; Papers ger022
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Research Materials, 1940-1996; 6; 0.45 cubic ft.
  - Jonas, H., "The Burden and Blessing of Mortality" (unpublished TS), 1991 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 33)
  - Jonas, L. "Mein Vater Siegfried Weiner (1886-1963)" (published), 1989 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 34)
  - Krohn, Der Philosophische Ökonom (published), 1996 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 35)
  - Lissner, "Adolph Lowe's Methodological Alternative for Economic Research and Policy" (published), 1981 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 36)
  - Lüdke, "Phönix, Asche und Scheiterhaufen der zerfall der Frankfurter Schule" (published), 1977 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 37)
  - Magnan de Bornier, "Le Modèle à Trois Secteurs de Lowe" (published), 1980 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 38)
  - Neisser, "Equilibrium Dynamics, Behavior Dynamics, Stability of Movement" (published), 1961 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 39)
  - Schwartzmann, "Competition and Efficiency" (unpublished TS), 1972 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 40)
  - Shaikh, "Relative Prices and Inter-Industrial Relations" (unpublished TS), 1976 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 41)
  - Simon, "Invention and Cost Reduction in Technological Change" (unpublished TS), ca. 1970 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 42)
  - Staudinger, Untitled Essay (unpublished TS), 1978 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 43)
  - Vickers, "Purpose and Force; The Bases of Order" (published), 1940 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 44)
  - Vickers, "Incomes and Earnings --A Steady State?" (published), ca. 1960 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 45)
  - Vickers, "The Management of Conflict" (published), 1972 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 46)
  - Vickers, "Towards a More Stable State" (published), 1972 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 47)
  - Vickers, Copies of Vickers-Simon Correspondence (unpublished TS), 1973 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 48)
  - Vickers, "Whither the Mixed Economy?" (published), 1973 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 49)
  - Vickers, "Some Implications of Systems Thinking" (unpublished TS), 1978 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 50)
  - Vickers, "The Poverty of Problem-Solving" (unpublished TS), 1980 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 51)
  - Vickers, "Autonomous Yet Responsible?" (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 52)
  - Vickers, "The Weakness of Western Culture" (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 53)
  - Wade, "E.F. Schumacher, Cutting Technology Down to Size" (published), 1975 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 54)
  - Unidentified author, "Das Materialismus: Seine Geschichte und Substanz" (unpublished TS), ca. 1975 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 55)
  - Unidentified author, Chapters of a Dissertation on Marx (unpublished TS), 1976 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 56)
  - Unidentified author, "Parallelism and Complementarity: Spinoza's Solution ..." (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 57)
  - Unidentified author, Untitled Fragment (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 58)
- Miscellaneous Professional Documents, 1918-1989; 7; 0.40 cubic ft.
  This series consists of materials that document Lowe's professional activities. Included are minutes of several academic conferences in which he took part, minutes of the New School's Study Group on Germany (1943), clippings and correspondence concerning his receipt of various awards and honors, contracts with publishers, reviews of and advertisements for his books, assorted publications of the New School for Social Research, and a 1988 interview published in Die Zeit, a leading German newspaper.
  - Ministry of War Documents (Copies made by Gerald Feldman), 1918-1919 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 59)
  - Conference Minutes, Abteilung für Weltwirtschaftskunde und internationale Konjuncturforschung (unpublished TS), 1926 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 60)
  - "Abschiedsworte des Dekans an den scheidenden Kollegen Löwe..." (unpublished TS), 1931 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 61)
  - Reviews, etc., for Economics and Sociology, 1935-1936 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 62)
  - Minutes, New School Study Group on Germany, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 63)
  - New School for Social Research Publications and Clippings, 1959-1987 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 64)
  - Publishing Contracts, 1963-1989 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 65)
  - Reviews, Announcements, Etc., for On Economic Knowledge, 1965-1970 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 66)
  - Review of Heilbroner, Economic Means and Social Ends, ca. 1970 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 67)
  - Adolph Lowe Institute for Economic Research, 1978-1995 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 68)
  - Veblen-Commons Award, 1979-1980 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 69)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary of University in Exile; Grosse Bundesverdienstkreuz, 1984 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 70)
  - New School Observer, 1984-1989 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 71)
  - Die Zeit Interview, 1988 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 72)
  - Reviews, etc., for Has Freedom a Future?, 1989 (Box 5 (7-Miscellaneous Professional Documents), Folder 73)